Hi. How are your outlines coming along?
Have you got them done?
Yes. I have outlined the structure of my presentation
Now I am working on the content.
Great. That means you have a good “recipe” done
What recipe? I’m not cooking
I’m writing my presentation
I know. But I’ve heard an interesting example
It says preparing for a presentation is like making a cake
That IS interesting
So, what is the “recipe” for a presentation?
A good recipe is the structure
plus an outline for each section
You need to have the outlines first
and then follow the instructions carefully
in order to make the cake
Very true
Without the outlines
the content may end up being vague and unorganized
So now you’re writing the content
It’s like mixing all the ingredients together in a bowl
You’re right
That’s the main body of my presentation
I need to write down what I want the audience to hear
Those are my “ingredients.”
When you write down the main points
focus on the core message
and keep it clear and concise
Avoid using jargon that people won’t understand
Your audience won’t have time to check the dictionary
And avoid abbreviations, acronyms and initials, too
Presentations are spoken
so choose terms people are very familiar with
The “rule of three” is very practical
Limit your main points to three
and then expand on each of them if necessary
Keep them simple and short.
I totally agree
People lose interest in long sentences
and information overload
Those are all good tips
for getting the main points ready
When you’re done with the content
it’s time to put the “cake” in the oven to cook
So what’s the next step after “baking”?
Remove the cake from the oven, and cool it
You “cool” your presentation draft
when you edit and revise it
Right. Editing and revising take time
To revise the first draft, read it aloud
and listen to the rhythm of the words
Ensure the language is appropriate and easy to understand
You should probably review it more than once
and cut anything that is not relevant to your core message
After working on your revision
you can start rehearsing your talk
Wow, sounds perfect
I can’t wait to make my very own “cake.”